JIESHAN CHEN

Address: Level 5/13 Garden St, Eveleigh NSW 2015, Australia

Phone: (+61) 452 234 123 Email: Jieshan.Chen@data61.csiro.au Website: https://chenjshnn.github.io/

RESEARCH INTEREST

My work lies in the fields of software engineering, deep learning, and human-computer interaction. My research focus on guaranteeing and supporting responsible software development by design by AI/ML techniques. Specifically, my research includes examining and mitigating accessibility and ethical issues in apps and enhancing the productivity during software development using responsible AI techniques.

EDUCATION

Australian National University

August 2018 – December 2022

Ph.D. in Computer Science

Thesis: Improving the Efficiency of Mobile User Interface Development through Semantic and Data-Driven Analyses Supervisors: Zhenchang Xing and Chunyang Chen

Sun Yat-Sen University

August 2014 – June 2018

Bachelor in Statistics, School of Mathematics

Honors Graduate

Overall GPA: 3.8/4.0 (89/100)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

CSIRO's Data61 January 2022– Present

Research Scientist – Software Engineering for AI (SE4AI)

- Designed a dark pattern detection system and implement into an Android app.
- Supervised students to investigate how designers design the AI apps to allow better interact with the end-users, and summarized
 three primary types of interaction patterns, namely minimal feedback, general feedback, and fine-grained feedback, and ten
 secondary and nine tertiary patterns.
- Presented dark patterns demo to different stakeholders and companies.

Apple Inc.

March 2021-September 2021

AI/ML Research Intern - Machine Learning + UI Understanding Team

- Prototyped a system using different strategies for enhancing 100% icon accessibility for screen readers (accepted at CHI'22)
- Prototyped a system to extract interactions from usage recordings to assist developers and end-users (wrote a paper and uploaded to ArXiv)

Guangzhou, Haolan Information Technology Co., Ltd

November 2017 – March 2018

Artificial Intelligence Research Intern

Project Topic: Chinese Medicine's Image Recognition Project based on Deep Learning

- Collaborated in a six-person team of software development engineers, algorithm engineers to develop an Android application for instantly identifying the Chinese traditional herbal medicine.
- Implemented Image Enhancement Technology to augment the sparse raw data (150 pictures, 14 classes), developed image classification model achieving 95% accuracy in testing data; received great feedback from the client.

Guangdong Province Key Laboratory of Computational Science

July 2016 - November 2016

Data Mining Team – Researcher

Project Topic: Efficient Movie Recommendation System for Large-Scale Dataset

• Implemented Matrix Factorization Model in C & Python for training the large-scale rating matrix from Netflix.

- Utilized MPI to parallelize the training process, up to 25 times faster than the original one.
- Optimized the model by an online learning framework, Alternating Direction Method of Multipliers (ADMM), to quickly adapt the model to new records.

MENTORSHIP

PhD Student

 Mingyue Yuan (Feb. 2023-) CSIRO's Data61 & University of New South Wales (Co-supervised with Aaron Quigley, Zhenchang Xing, Gelareh Mohammadi)

Master/Bachelor students - final year project

- (2023 Monash) Ziqi Zhao
- (2022 Monash) Jason Siu (will submit paper to UIST2023)
- (2020-2021 ANU) Xincheng Xu, Yukang Liu
- (2019-2020 ANU) Zhaowen Xu, Kexin Zhang, Mulong Xie (published FSE2020),
- (2018-2019 ANU) Kai Xi

Research Courses

• (2023-2024 Monash – FIT 4701) Alex Zhou, Sam Howard, Nobert Bayer, Yicheng Peng, Prithviram Prabhuram, Chen Liu

SERVICE

Program Committee

- International Conference on Software and System Processes (ICSSP'23)
- IEEE International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE'22- Industry Track)
- ACM CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI'22-Computational UI Workshop)
- The Mining Software Repositories (MSR'22-Shadow PC, MSE'23-Junior PC)

Reviewer

- IEEE Conference on Virtual Reality and 3D User Interfaces (IEEE VR'23)
- ACM CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI'22, CHI'23)
- The Mining Software Repositories (MSR'22, MSR'23)
- ACM international joint conference on pervasive and ubiquitous computing (UbiComp'22)
- International Journal of Human-Computer Interaction (IJHCI'22)
- IEEE International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE'22)
- ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (UIST'22)
- IEEE Transactions on Software Engineering (TSE'22, TSE '23)
- Information and Software Technology (IST Journal'21)

HONORS & AWARDS

CSIRO SCS Biannual Awards - Women in Science Career Award	June 2023
ACM SIGSOFT Distinguished Paper Award in ICSE 2020	July 2020
Google PhD Fellowship Nomination	2020
ANU HDR Fee Remission Merit Scholarship	2018-2022
ANU Ph.D. Scholarship (International) Full-Time	2018-2021
Honors Graduate of Sun Yat-Sen University	June 2018
Second Class Scholarship of Sun Yat-Sen University (Top 10%)	2017
Meritorious Winners in Interdisciplinary Contest in Modeling	January 2017
The Most Commercial Potential Award in Intel Cup Parallel Application Challenge	October 2016
Second Prize in China Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling	September 2016
Third Class Scholarship of Sun Yat-Sen University (Top 15%)	2016
Second Class Scholarship of Sun Yat-Sen University (Top 10%)	2015

PUBLICATIONS

[UIST 2023] Unveiling the Tricks: Automated Detection of Dark Patterns in Mobile Applications

<u>Jieshan Chen</u>, Jiamou Sun, Sidong Feng, Zhenchang Xing, Qinghua Lu, Xiwei Xu, Chunyang Chen To appear

[Preprint 2023] Towards Real Smart Apps: Investigating Human-AI Interactions in Smartphone On-Device AI Apps

Jason Ching Yuen Siu, <u>Jieshan Chen</u>, Yujin Huang, Zhenchang Xing, Chunyang Chen July 2023. <u>PDF</u>

[Preprint 2023] Prompt Sapper: A LLM-Empowered Production Tool for Building AI Chains

Yu Cheng, <u>Jieshan Chen</u>, Qing Huang, Zhenchang Xing, Xiwei Xu, Qinghua Lu June 2023. PDF

[Preprint 2022] Extracting Replayable Interactions from Videos of Mobile App Usage

<u>Jieshan Chen</u>, Amanda Swearngin, Jason Wu, Titus Barik, Jeffrey Nichols and Xiaoyi Zhang. July 2022. <u>PDF</u>

[CHI 2022] Towards Complete Icon Labeling in Mobile Applications

<u>Jieshan Chen</u>, Amanda Swearngin, Jason Wu, Titus Barik, Jeffrey Nichols and Xiaoyi Zhang. PDF · Talk. Acceptance Rate 12.5% (324/2,597)

[ESEC/FSE 2020] Object Detection for Graphical User Interface: Old Fashioned or Deep Learning or a Combination?

<u>Jieshan Chen</u>, Mulong Xie, Zhenchang Xing, Chunyang Chen, Xiwei Xu, Liming Zhu and Guoqiang Li. <u>PDF</u> · <u>Tool</u> · <u>Video</u> · <u>Code</u> · Acceptance Rate 28% (101/360)

[TOSEM 2020] Wireframe-based UI Design Search through Image Autoencoder.

<u>Jieshan Chen</u>, Chunyang Chen, Zhenchang Xing, Xin Xia, Liming Zhu, John Grundy, and Jinshui Wang. *Present in ICSE 2021*.

 $\underline{PDF} \cdot \underline{Video} \cdot \underline{Code}$

[ICSE 2020] Unblind Your Apps: Predicting Natural-Language Labels for Mobile GUI Components by Deep Learning.

Jieshan Chen, Chunyang Chen, Zhenchang Xing, Xiwei Xu, Liming Zhu, Guoqiang Li, and Jinshui Wang.

ACM SIGSOFT Distinguished Paper Award

PDF · Video · Code · Acceptance Rate 20.9% (129/617)

[IJCNN 2017] Ensemble Application of Convolutional and Recurrent Neural Networks for Multi-label Text Categorization.

Guibin Chen, Deheng Ye, Zhenchang Xing, <u>Jieshan Chen</u>, and Erik Cambria. PDF